[{"id": "5fe2583f658e585fda9cfa3e", "question": "Black Forest cake originates from which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a33a12f2a7826b9b8723", "question": "What country is the band \"Men Without Hats\" originally from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86c", "question": "What disease, caused by the bacteria Y. pestis, is spread by fleas and rats?", "answer": "Bubonic plague", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a186", "question": "In the cartoon \"Wacky Races\", who drove the Crimson Haybaler?", "answer": "The Red Max", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029e41cad1ec93f27df755", "question": "What year was Strongbow cider introduced to the market?", "answer": "1962", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f8abfa5fdd6dd25324f0", "question": "Which city is home to Colman's mustard?", "answer": "Norwich", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985c", "question": "In the movie \"Howl's Moving Castle\", Calcifer was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Billy Crystal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b154", "question": "What 15th century Incan site was discovered in 1911 by Hiram Bingham?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66216a5bfecdd737e0841", "question": "Who was on the first cover of \"Rolling Stone\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af983c3aeb0982ee4559549", "question": "In the movie \"Star Wars: Episode VII - The Force Awakens\", who kills Han Solo?", "answer": "Kylo Ren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f0", "question": "What name was adopted by boxing champion Cassius Marcellus Clay Jr.?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "593c4bdab8198b9a2b077966", "question": "Which \"Die Hard\" film also stars Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Die Hard with a Vengence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a7", "question": "In the movie \"Live And Let Die\", what ability does Solitaire lose after sleeping with Bond?", "answer": "Her psychic ability", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e3", "question": "What plant does the vanilla bean come from?", "answer": "The orchid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c779", "question": "What aquatic reptile can hold its breath under water for up to 15 minutes?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7cc", "question": "What is a traditional karate uniform called?", "answer": "Gi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab954286faa38a764be514", "question": "What year did BMW debut the M5?", "answer": "1985", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f53", "question": "Who is Dinah, whom Alice thinks about nostalgically as she falls down the rabbit hole to Wonderland?", "answer": "Her cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f3", "question": "Whose remains were thrown into the Seine River on May 30, 1431?", "answer": "Joan of Arc's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47b", "question": "Which stretch of water is Europe's most northern boundary?", "answer": "Arctic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c574", "question": "Which element has the chemical symbol \"No\"?", "answer": "Nobelium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae56", "question": "During the 1920s, gangster Al Capone ruled over what city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba6f4874c93a3298b215e", "question": "What is Paul Stanley's persona name in the band KISS?", "answer": "The Starchild", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b3724d1c3f17ccc40c8e23", "question": "What English party was politician Arthur Hayday associated with?", "answer": "Labour Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c271", "question": "What is March's birthstone?", "answer": "Aquamarine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca4b", "question": "What bird has the biggest wingspan?", "answer": "Albatross", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84a", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find hepatocytes?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8b", "question": "What former World Heavyweight Champion boxer was nicknamed \"The Brown Bomber\"?", "answer": "Joe Louis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65805ae7e414034b5aee5", "question": "In the Bible in the book of Job, who begins the first discourse to Job?", "answer": "Eliphaz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4a2e49076251badbeab0", "question": "Where did the phrase \"Don\u2019t Mess With Texas\" come from?", "answer": "An anti-litter campaign -- The campaign idea was \u201cdon\u2019t litter in Texas, don\u2019t mess up Texas,\u201d but it became so much more.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb1137e83c707845b210b", "question": "Which planet was discovered by mathematical prediction before it was directly observed?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ae", "question": "What year marked the start of the construction of the Colosseum?", "answer": "72 AD", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8e9", "question": "\"I shall please\" is the Latin translation of what medical treatment?", "answer": "Placebo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd5", "question": "Who was \"The Wizard of Menlo Park\"?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a194", "question": "Raymond Burr played a journalist named Steve Martin in the American version of which giant monster movie?", "answer": "Godzilla, King of the Monsters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c8", "question": "What is New York City's most popular nickname?", "answer": "The Big Apple", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e147743dd42e4a67cb8d3e9", "question": "Which Star Trek film features both Captain Kirk and Captain Picard?", "answer": "Star Trek : Generations", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338903", "question": "What Ian Fleming novel's title is the nickname of the character Francisco Scaramanga?", "answer": "The Man with the Golden Gun", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339008", "question": "What is Dagwood Bumstead's dog's name?", "answer": "Daisy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84d", "question": "What is the Hebrew word for peace, used as both a greeting and a farewell?", "answer": "Shalom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06b", "question": "In which film did Donna Summer make her debut as an aspiring disco singer?", "answer": "Thank God It's Friday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942d", "question": "Who played the role of O-Ren Ishii in the 2003 movie \"Kill Bill: Vol. 1\"?", "answer": "Lucy Liu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339732", "question": "How many hard-boiled eggs does Paul Newman's character eat in \"Cool Hand Luke\"?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a10b20565ad31a57c79f", "question": "Which country created the official marathon length of 26.2 miles?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60173fab44491cbd7c5a17b4", "question": "What general commanded the American Expeditionary Forces on the Western Front during World War I?", "answer": "John Joseph \"Black Jack\" Pershing GCB", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5902a0d3cad1ec93f27df771", "question": "How much larger is UK pint compared to the US pint?", "answer": "About 20%, or 95 mL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601600fffe83fe1f2a824c5a", "question": "Why did famous Civil War photographer Mathew Brady go broke?", "answer": "No one wanted to remember the war", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a09a", "question": "Elvis's manager, Colonel Tom Parker, had what earlier act?", "answer": "Dancing chickens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f1", "question": "What can you figure out about the weather by counting the cricket chirps?", "answer": "Temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a281", "question": "Who preceded Phil Collins as the lead singer of Genesis?", "answer": "Peter Gabriel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcb", "question": "What's the ancient Greek word for \"great city\"?", "answer": "Megalopolis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcdc", "question": "What common item is usually made up of twelve pentagons and twenty hexagons?", "answer": "A soccer ball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015fc7cfe83fe1f2a824c41", "question": "According to Greek mythology, who was the Greek god of music?", "answer": "Apollo is the god of music as well as archery, poetry, healing, prophecy, manly beauty, plague, knowledge and arts.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3f", "question": "What duo composed the operetta \"Porgy and Bess\"?", "answer": "George Gershwin and Ira Gershwin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cbd3877e98cb97778a20", "question": "In what U.S. city is South Beach located?", "answer": "Miami Beach, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59bb288fc9bff04efae6d751", "question": "Who wrote the 1969 novel \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Mario Puzo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e72", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Butterflies Are Free\"?", "answer": "Edward Albert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338abb", "question": "Who was the valet that followed Phileas Fogg when he traveled around the world in 80 days?", "answer": "Jean Passepartout", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef7", "question": "The Gold Rush of 1849 occurred in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c89e08011619dd6d41548a", "question": "What is the name of the reality series Token made featuring mobility scooter-bound Cartman in the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Here Comes Fatty Doo Doo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e90", "question": "What is the only signed work of Michelangelo?", "answer": "The Pieta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8aa6301dd7bf43be5e759", "question": "Who designed the Sydney Opera House?", "answer": "Jorn Utzon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c171", "question": "What is the alternative name of scallions?", "answer": "Spring onions or green onions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2f", "question": "Bernard Marx and Lenina Crowne are the main characters of what novel?", "answer": "A Brave New World", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5d2e6ce05a3942286e29", "question": "Which song was tapped out on the giant keyboard in \"Big\"?", "answer": "\"Heart and Soul\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb0ccf83302ff91e464a0", "question": "What year was the luxury brand \"Tiffany & Co.\" founded?", "answer": "1837", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339343", "question": "Who was the cook on the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Hop Sing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a798", "question": "What five countries border Peru?", "answer": "Colombia, Ecuador, Brazil, Bolivia and Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c151", "question": "What sport is Pele associated with?", "answer": "Soccer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e44", "question": "What American TV actor plays himself as a fallen angel in Wim Wenders' \"Wings of Desire\"?", "answer": "Peter Falk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe698e720565ad31a57c73d", "question": "Which coffee innovation was developed by German housewife Melitta Bentz?", "answer": "Coffee filter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aafe", "question": "In what country is Thunder Bay?", "answer": "Canada\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3acbff048f679a45ab2e", "question": "Atoms of the same chemical element but with different atomic masses are known as what?", "answer": "Isotopes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e6bb49fb6c85e9e634ff53", "question": "Which American female vocalist had a hit in 1985 with \"We Don't Need Another Hero\"?", "answer": "Tina Turner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049e53cf93664eb10486b3", "question": "The Koson District is a district in the Qashqadaryo Region of which country?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5977432a284458f1d7854427", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a575", "question": "In what US city can tourists visit the Space Needle?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c348", "question": "Who is considered the father of the computer due to his plans for a steam-powered difference engine?", "answer": "Charles Babbage", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32b", "question": "Which great American inventor died in October, 1931?\u00a0", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396fb", "question": "After his stint as Robin, what persona new did Dick Grayson adopt?", "answer": "Nightwing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e93f47ccba3ffe45786cc", "question": "What year was Buddy Holly born?", "answer": "1936", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339236", "question": "What is the real first name of rock star Prince?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a1", "question": "What country is named for the founder of the \"Friars Preachers\" religious order?", "answer": "The Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51bfdff04d658268c9313", "question": "Who killed the Portuguese explorer Ferdinand Magellan in 1521?", "answer": "Lapu-Lapu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989acb0cb8751d53e7d760c", "question": "Which two twin primes add up to 360?", "answer": "179 and 181", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae76", "question": "What Confederate general opened fire on Fort Sumter, beginning the Civil War?", "answer": "General Beauregard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa5843c73aa70ea0b70b3a", "question": "Which U.S. state has \"Salus Populi Suprema Lex Esto\" as its state motto?", "answer": "Missouri (The phrase translates to \"Let the welfare of the people be the supreme law\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e4", "question": "A skulk is a group of which animals?", "answer": "Foxes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea8", "question": "Which French King Louis was called the Sun King?", "answer": "Louis XIV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c134", "question": "In motor racing, what color flag is used to communicate stopping of the racing session?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a987", "question": "What city named its airport after Louis Armstrong?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b52", "question": "In Greek mythology, who killed the Gorgon?", "answer": "Perseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b461", "question": "What year was boxer John L. Sullivan born?", "answer": "1858", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e5f11e3d274615ecf51453c", "question": "\"Oscitation\", is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Yawning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6a", "question": "In \"Alice in Wonderland\", what is the last thing that disappears on the Cheshire Cat?", "answer": "Its smile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c740", "question": "What is the most populous bird in the world?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc2", "question": "Artist Bono shared Time's \"Man of the Year\" honors with what other man and his wife?", "answer": "Bill Gates", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b733364247bf200fb86f", "question": "Who wrote \"The Scarlatti Inheritance\"?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b601", "question": "Ham was one of the sons of what Biblical patriarch?", "answer": "Noah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff6686852a821ff76ae8b04", "question": "Who are the first people known to have consumed chocolate?", "answer": "There is evidence that the ancient Olmecs of what is now Mexico consumed chocolate beverages as far back as 1900 BC.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9e0fae748bb36357acdf1", "question": "What does VHS stand for?", "answer": "Video Home System", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920b", "question": "What early 1990's dance craze was launched by \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "The Bartman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe77365eec85e375820b306", "question": "What country has the largest forest found within a city?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a9", "question": "What city hosted the 1992 Summer Olympic Games?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa1", "question": "What TV show's cops operate out of a converted church they call \"the Barn\"?", "answer": "The Shield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af9874eaeb0982ee4559552", "question": "What is believed to be the first political cartoon published in colonial America?", "answer": "Join or Die Cartoon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e7ec06d333868d34d745", "question": "Who did Mao Zedong lead in the \"Long March\" in 1934-35?", "answer": "Chinese Red Army", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338985", "question": "What is the only nationality mentioned in the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\"?", "answer": "French", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2d", "question": "What was Mark Twain's real name?", "answer": "Samuel Clemens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af38", "question": "Who was killed in 1804 in a duel with Vice President Aaron Burr?", "answer": "Alexander Hamilton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339125", "question": "\"Samson and Delilah\" is an opera by which French composer?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Sa\u00ebns", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35e", "question": "Where is the International Court of Justice?", "answer": "The Hague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ab", "question": "What would you suffer from with Hypotension?", "answer": "Low blood pressure\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bf", "question": "How old was Marilyn Monroe when she died?", "answer": "36", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929c", "question": "Apart from the piano, what other musical instrument does Dr. Sheldon Cooper from the TV show \"The Big Band Theory\"?", "answer": "The theramin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f20", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Rosemary Murphy and Jennifer Jason Leigh?", "answer": "Dorothy Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea43beff048f679a45ab87", "question": "What enzyme is responsible for breaking down starches?", "answer": "Amylase", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c772", "question": "Which planet is named for the Roman God who was the son of Juno and Jupiter?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049cd4cf93664eb10486aa", "question": "What is the name of the avenue that lies between 12th and 14th Avenue in San Francisco?", "answer": "Funston Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab38", "question": "Which ocean is Cook Islands located in?", "answer": "Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffcfbbd9dc5ec6cd98a8317", "question": "What painting is featured prominently in the 2007 film \"St Trinian's\"?", "answer": "Johannes Vermeer's\u00a0\"Girl with a Pearl Earring\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339990", "question": "What was Lucy\u2019s last name on the TV series \"I Love Lucy\"?", "answer": "Ricardo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb357d02627b8fe95581be5", "question": "Within the English language, what author has the most published books?", "answer": "L. Ron Hubbard", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b690", "question": "The tuxedo got its name from what?", "answer": "A town in New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af32", "question": "What war was fought from 1754 to 1763?", "answer": "The Seven Year's War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81d61d0de9af39e9d468e", "question": "Who was the only president to serve in both World Wars?", "answer": "Dwight D Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca49", "question": "American Garrett Morgan patented what in 1923?", "answer": "The Traffic Signal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb2", "question": "Whose adventures on TV take place on the fictional Island of Sodor?", "answer": "Thomas the Tank Engine's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea43dfff048f679a45ab8a", "question": "What condition refers to a low oxygen level in the blood?", "answer": "Hypoxia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24e", "question": "Who had a hit with the song \"Jacob's Ladder\"?", "answer": "Huey Lewis and the News", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b1", "question": "What must a mole do every four hours or it will die?", "answer": "Eat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c4", "question": "What term for a rocket's propulsive force is calculated by multiplying its exhaust velocity by the burn rate of its fuel?", "answer": "Thrust", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6c", "question": "What was the name of the 80\u2019s band formed by Roland Orzabal and Curt Smith?", "answer": "Tears for Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ad", "question": "When did J. D. Salinger publish the novel \"The Catcher in the Rye\"?", "answer": "1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339951", "question": "The movie \"Reservoir Dogs\" marked the directorial debut of whom?", "answer": "Quentin Tarentino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3cdec73aa70ea0b70af0", "question": "A bouzouki is a stringed instrument from which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b933", "question": "What meal-in-a-box is called the San Francisco treat?", "answer": "Rice-a-Roni", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523c4c736d4be723796b37", "question": "What is the name of the highway that travels through all ten Canadian provinces?", "answer": "Trans-Canada Highway, or Route Transcanadienne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc3", "question": "Albania has coasts on which two seas?", "answer": "Adriatic and Ionian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab6", "question": "Who wrote, TIdings of Comfort and Joy in 1997?", "answer": "T. Davis Bunn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e9a606d333868d34d757", "question": "During World War II, the U.S. purchase more than 150 million pounds of what to feed its troops?", "answer": "SPAM", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338885", "question": "What does a bibliophile enjoy?", "answer": "Books", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f702ff048f679a45aae2", "question": "What kind of scientist was Luther Burbank?", "answer": "Botanist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935f", "question": "What was in the jaws of the swordfish mounted on the wall in the Addams Family house?", "answer": "A human leg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d98", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Joad?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70d", "question": "What is the name given to glittery strings hung on Christmas trees?", "answer": "Tinsel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c852", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the pyloris?", "answer": "The stomach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594a64462ebb971c1417fba2", "question": "Who was the first woman to swim across Lake Ontario?", "answer": "Marilyn Bell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da3", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Tulliver?", "answer": "George Eliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf24", "question": "What does the KonMari Method focus on?", "answer": "Tidying up", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339beb", "question": "What year saw the debut of the TV show \"Wheel of Fortune\"?", "answer": "1975", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1bd", "question": "What US president was a personal friend of John Kenneth Galbraith?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66645a5bfecdd737e0868", "question": "What is the highest possible FICO score?", "answer": "850", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6f", "question": "What was the name of Rhett and Scarlett\u2019s daughter in \"Gone With the Wind\"?", "answer": "Bonnie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af47", "question": "Who was the fourth president of the United States?", "answer": "James Madison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88b", "question": "What capital city is built around the famous Plaza Mayor and Puerta del Sol?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d46fd6f8e329de4f87788a", "question": "Which actor's real name is Emanuel Goldenberg?", "answer": "Edward G. Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae7", "question": "What is a Supersonic Combustion Ramjet better known as?", "answer": "Scramjet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef96166ce05a3942286e9a", "question": "In what Disney movie would you find the character of Briar Rose?", "answer": "\"Sleeping Beauty\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b243", "question": "What king was executed for the excesses of his inquisitional \"Star Chamber\"?", "answer": "Charles I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec25668dc25ca9e12ef63e", "question": "What Ray Bradbury novel is named for temperature at which paper catches fire?", "answer": "Fahrenheit 451", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af255deb63e5727cf5a483b", "question": "Which of Antigua and Barbuda\u2019s islands is the largest by land area?", "answer": "Antigua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf1", "question": "What year was actor Heath Ledger born in?", "answer": "1979", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162ca3f01ec323f8491731", "question": "What is the second largest country in the world?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eaf96f83302ff91e46494", "question": "What are juvenile goats called?", "answer": "Kids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe379810ada16518afdc055", "question": "Which event is widely considered to be the official start of the Holocaust?", "answer": "Kristallnacht", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d75", "question": "Who was the first female comic to be called over to the couch by Johnny Carson?", "answer": "Ellen DeGeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4136ff048f679a45ab6e", "question": "What connects flower buds to the stem?", "answer": "Sepals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c94c", "question": "Pnigerophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Smothering", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7a49ff048f679a45abea", "question": "What part of the brain is responsible for vision?", "answer": "Occipital", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbff36ce05a3942286f07", "question": "Which two popular actors starred in the lead roles in the film \"Rounders\"?", "answer": "Matt Damon and Edward Norton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd193ec223966ae8f88c0", "question": "What was Joan Crawford's last film?", "answer": "\"Trog\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3e", "question": "How many children did Rob and Laura Petrie have on \"The Dick Van Dyke Show\"?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02a", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Franz Gutentag was once what?", "answer": "A Nazi war criminal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa55273838c5c8a417f23", "question": "Who discovered the life or death importance of washing hands while studying maternity wards?", "answer": "Ignaz Philipp Semmelweis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca54", "question": "Acceleration is the rate of change of what?", "answer": "Velocity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5d", "question": "Who wrote \"The Invisible Man\"?", "answer": "H.G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeff", "question": "What city hosted the Summer Olympics in 1996?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad7", "question": "What is the Christmas Carol \"O Christmas Tree\" known as in German?", "answer": "O Tannenbaum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f27", "question": "Who wrote \"Mein Kampf\" while in prison?", "answer": "Adolf Hitler", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcd", "question": "What TV show did \"Lou Grant\" spin off from?", "answer": "The Mary Tyler Moore Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb5", "question": "What was the better-known name of Margareta Zelle, exotic dancer?", "answer": "Mata Hari", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c209", "question": "Which country were the 1912 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c7940775fa611bce67db", "question": "How long is a tiger's tooth (canine teeth)?", "answer": "3 inches long", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2b", "question": "What Internet portal was sued for copyright infringement in 2000 by the star of \"Young Einstein\"?", "answer": "Yahoo!", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab972286faa38a764be526", "question": "Which car manufacturer was the first to include seat belts as a standard feature in their vehicles?", "answer": "Saab", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d82", "question": "What film's theme song is \"Nothing's Gonna Stop Us Now\", by Starship?", "answer": "Mannequin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7d02d877e98cb97778a5c", "question": "The Catedral de Sal, a cathedral carved entirely out of salt, is located in what country?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c6", "question": "What five-letter word did Time magazine coin in 1926 to refer to left-leaners?", "answer": "Pinko", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb1bf51f497e33de805791a", "question": "What is the oldest active ballpark in Major League Baseball?", "answer": "Fenway Park", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65ed21f3c0ead6880d630", "question": "What does the French dessert B\u00fbche de No\u00ebl represent?", "answer": "Yule log", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f5660b33a95c66dc4fe75d", "question": "Which British opera festival was started in 1934?", "answer": "Glyndebourne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b47d", "question": "What year saw the Battle of the Plains of Abraham?", "answer": "1759", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2c", "question": "In what sport are the Beaters in charge of batting away the Bludgers?", "answer": "Quidditch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2f", "question": "Who was the sadistic commander of the HMS Bounty?", "answer": "Captain Bligh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a590", "question": "What U.S. state is proud to call itself \"the Beaver State\"?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff66d0252a821ff76ae8b16", "question": "What item was banned by the U.S. government in 1943 due to a paper shortage?", "answer": "Sliced bread (Among other reasons, sliced bread required twice as much wax paper as unsliced bread.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5b", "question": "\"Cirque du Soleil\" was founded in what Canadian province?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd1", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"H\"?", "answer": "Hotel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1af", "question": "Which singer played \"Breathless Mahoney\" in the 1990 film \"Dick Tracy\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a534", "question": "What US city is located on the shores of Puget Sound?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f1693bf7c52aae91cc07ce", "question": "What year did Wilkie Collins publish the novel \"The Moonstone\"?", "answer": "1868", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899c2e60d398dc9cf7a6a5", "question": "Vesta is the Roman goddess of what?", "answer": "Hearth, home and family", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339613", "question": "What sport was featured in the 1985 movie \"Vision Quest\"?", "answer": "Wrestling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a610", "question": "What is the world\u2019s most southerly capital city?", "answer": "Wellington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b7", "question": "In which movie does Clint Eastwood utter the line 'Go ahead, make my day\"?", "answer": "Sudden Impact", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f621ff048f679a45aada", "question": "What is the gestation period of a Hippopotamus?", "answer": "Eight months", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e8", "question": "In the movie \"Raising Arizona\", what brand of diapers does Nicolas Cage steal from the convenience store?", "answer": "Huggies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf7", "question": "What is the best known artificial international language?", "answer": "Esperanto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f71", "question": "Which musical was based on H. G. Wells novel \"Kipps: The Story of a Simple Soul\"?", "answer": "Half a Sixpence", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a505", "question": "What name is given to the vast, treeless plains of South America?", "answer": "Pampas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b155", "question": "What year was Princess Diana born?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec84c6ec223966ae8f8802", "question": "In 1985, Patrick Ewing was the first No. 1 pick under what system?", "answer": "The draft lottery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339730", "question": "What is the name of the \"Brady Bunch\" dog?", "answer": "Tiger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c7", "question": "In The Simpsons, \"Over a century without a slogan\" is the slogan of which downtown Springfield department store?", "answer": "Costington's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66261a5bfecdd737e0844", "question": "How far from shore do international waters start?", "answer": "200 nautical miles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b1", "question": "What year saw the release of \"The Catcher in the Rye\"?", "answer": "1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea4466ff048f679a45ab8d", "question": "What snake will roll over and fake a gruesome death to confuse its attacker?", "answer": "Hog-nosed snake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c332", "question": "What was the purpose of the ancient medicinal confection made from the marshmallow plant?", "answer": "To treat irritated mucous membranes and increase the flow of breast milk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cefc0c4948005ec986edcdf", "question": "Who is the sixth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Kim Lip", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ab4501dd7bf43be5e766", "question": "What is a horizontal window above a doorway called?", "answer": "A transom window", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5d726ce05a3942286e2b", "question": "Which hit song is Norman Greenbaum known for?", "answer": "\"Spirit in the Sky\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a041", "question": "Kevin Spacey plays Francis Underwood in what Netflix original series?", "answer": "House of Cards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c5049076251badbead1", "question": "The term \"first family\" came into popularity under which U.S. President?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy -- Comedian/Kennedy impressionist Vaughn Meader titled his Grammy-winning 1962 album \"First Family\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "595247c2736d4be723796b73", "question": "What is the name of Lady Antebellum\u2019s first #1 hit?", "answer": "\"I Run To You\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97e", "question": "What would you add to a Welsh Rarebit to make a Buck Rarebit?", "answer": "Poached Egg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab65", "question": "What links Catalonia, Andalusia, Cantabria, Galicia?", "answer": "They are regions of Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb7", "question": "What bird is Britain's VTOL \"jump jet\" named for?", "answer": "The Harrier hawk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c775", "question": "The brains of what animal species are eaten as delicacy in South Asia and Africa?", "answer": "Monkeys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f2", "question": "Where would you find Olympus Mons?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca45", "question": "In the human body where is your occiput?", "answer": "Back of the head", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a148", "question": "In the TV series \"The Dukes of Hazzard\", what was painted on the top of their car?", "answer": "Confederate flag", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbe", "question": "Which war was fought along the 38th parallel?", "answer": "The Korean War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6f", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Missouri?", "answer": "Jefferson City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c884877e98cb977789e7", "question": "What US state shares the shortest border with Canada?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f39dff048f679a45aac1", "question": "What color is liquid oxygen?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cb70c02f96e155acab35d28", "question": "What is Chiroptophobia?", "answer": "Fear of Bats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff20ff931a458464a93c43a", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f22801dd7bf43be5e80d", "question": "What do skydivers traditionally do for their 100th jump?", "answer": "They skydive nude", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c78a", "question": "What is the chemical formula for ozone?", "answer": "O3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa96773838c5c8a417f45", "question": "What is a baby kangaroo called?", "answer": "Joey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600a2704e958e8c9f3127313", "question": "Where did the Mayflower land in New England in 1620?", "answer": "Cape Cod - The Mayflower sailed from England to the \u201cNew World,\u201d landing in Plymouth Harbor along the shores of Cape Cod.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59c1cde77bd84c0ea43ad431", "question": "In Norse mythology, what did Odin trade an eye for?", "answer": "Wisdom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feccd3aec223966ae8f88aa", "question": "What is the name of the event where tributes are chosen for \"The Hunger Games\"?", "answer": "The Reaping", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca83", "question": "Which scientist is credited with inventing margarine?", "answer": "Hippolyte Mege-Mouries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4b70b06d333868d34d6f7", "question": "Refugees on which ship were refused entry to both Cuba and the U.S. in 1939?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c2", "question": "What is the more common name for Naris?", "answer": "Nostril", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f19", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Raymond Massey and Henry Fonda?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f0", "question": "Which actress was jailed in 1982 for tax evasion?", "answer": "Sophia Loren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a8", "question": "The World's first \"sister cities\" were what Spanish city and its US midwestern namesake?", "answer": "Toledo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b51", "question": "What is the better known name of musician born Reginald Kenneth Dwight?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339154", "question": "In \"The Saint\" series of books, what is Inspector Teal's full name?", "answer": "Claud Eustace Teal", "category": "arts"}]